DOCTOR: I'm a time traveller.
DOCTOR: I'm stuck in 1969.
MARTHA: We're stuck.
MARTHA: All of space and time, he promised me.
MARTHA: Now I've got a job in a shop
MARTHA: I've got to support him!
MALCOLM: I'm sorry
SALLY: I've seen this bit before.
DOCTOR: Quite possibly.
SALLY: 1969, that's where you're talking from?
DOCTOR: 'Fraid so.
SALLY: But you're replying to me.
SALLY: You can't know exactly what I'm gonna say
SALLY: 40 years before I say it!
DOCTOR: 38.
LARRY: I'm getting this down!
LARRY: I'm writing in your bits.
SALLY: How?
SALLY: How is this possible?
SALLY: Tell me.
LARRY: Not so fast.
DOCTOR: People don't understand time.
DOCTOR: It's not what you think it is.
SALLY: Then what is it?
DOCTOR: Complicated.
SALLY: Tell me.
DOCTOR: Very complicated.
SALLY: I'm clever and I'm listening.
SALLY: And don't patronise me because people have died
SALLY: and I'm not happy.
SALLY: Tell me!
DOCTOR: People assume that time is a strict progression of cause to effect
LARRY: Of course he can't hear us.
DOCTOR: but actually from a non-linear
DOCTOR: it's more like a big ball of wibbly-wobbly
SALLY: Like you can hear me.
DOCTOR: timey-wimey stuff.
SALLY: Yeah, I've seen this bit before.
SALLY: You said that sentence got away from you.
DOCTOR: It got away from me, yeah.
SALLY: Next thing you're going to say is
DOCTOR: Well, I can hear you.
SALLY: This isn't possible.
LARRY: It's brilliant!
DOCTOR: Not hear you exactly
SALLY: You're going to need it.
LARRY: Always gives me the shivers, that bit.
SALLY: How can you know what I'm going to say?
DOCTOR: Look to your left.
LARRY: What does he mean by, "Look to your left"?
LARRY: I've written tons about that on the forums.
LARRY: I think it's a political statement.
SALLY: He means you.
SALLY: What are you doing?
LARRY: I'm writing in your bits.
DOCTOR: I've got a copy of the finished transcript.
LARRY: So I've got a complete transcript of the whole conversation.
LARRY: Wait until this hits the net.
LARRY: This will explode the egg forums.
SALLY: How can you have a copy of the finished transcript?
SALLY: How could he get the transcript?
SALLY: It is still being written.
DOCTOR: I'm a time traveller.
DOCTOR: I got it in the future.
SALLY: Okay, let me get my head 'round this.
SALLY: You're reading from a transcript of a conversation you're still
BEN: You're in Hull.
SALLY: Wibbly-wobbly, timey-wimey.
SALLY: Gimme a name.
SALLY: Actually, never mind that.
SALLY: (To Larry): You can do shorthand?
LARRY: So?
DOCTOR: What matters is we can communicate.
DOCTOR: We have got big problems now.
DOCTOR: They've taken the blue box, haven't they?
DOCTOR: The angels have the phone box.
LARRY: The angels have the phone box!
DOCTOR: That's me.
LARRY: That's my favourite, I've got it on a tee-shirt!
SALLY: What do you mean, angels?
SALLY: You mean those statue things?
DOCTOR: Creatures from another world.
SALLY: But they're just statues.
DOCTOR: Only when you see them.
SALLY: What does that mean?
DOCTOR: Lonely assassins, they were called.
DOCTOR: No-one knows where they came from.
DOCTOR: They're as old as the universe, or very nearly.
DOCTOR: They've survived this long as they have the most perfect
DOCTOR: defence system ever evolved.
DOCTOR: They are quantum-locked.
DOCTOR: They don't exist when being observed.
DOCTOR: The moment they're seen by any other living creature they
DOCTOR: freeze into rock.
DOCTOR: It's a fact of their biology.
DOCTOR: In the sight of any living thing
DOCTOR: they literally turn to stone.
DOCTOR: And you can't k*ll a stone.
DOCTOR: Course, a stone can't k*ll you either.
DOCTOR: But then you turn your head away
DOCTOR: then you blink
DOCTOR: yes it can!
SALLY: Don't take your eyes off that.
DOCTOR: That's why they cover their eyes.
DOCTOR: They're coming.
LARRY: They're looking at each other.
DOCTOR: Their greatest asset is their greatest curse.
DOCTOR: They can never be seen.
DOCTOR: The loneliest creatures in the universe.
MALCOLM: I'm sorry
DOCTOR: And I'm sorry, Billy, I am very, very sorry.
DOCTOR: it's up to you now.
SALLY: What am I supposed to do?
DOCTOR: The blue box, it's my time machine.
DOCTOR: There is a world of time energy in there they
DOCTOR: could feast on forever.
DOCTOR: The damage they can do can switch off the sun.
DOCTOR: You have got to send it back to me!
SALLY: How?
SALLY: Kathy?
LARRY: And that's okay.
DOCTOR: There's no more from you on the transcript
DOCTOR: that's all I've got.
DOCTOR: I dunno what stopped you talking, but I can guess.
DOCTOR: but I know everything you're going to say.
DOCTOR: The angels are coming for you.
DOCTOR: Your life could depend on this.
DOCTOR: Don't blink!
DOCTOR: Don't even blink.
DOCTOR: Blink and you're dead.
DOCTOR: They are fast, faster than you can believe.
DOCTOR: Don't turn your back.
DOCTOR: Don't turn your back, don't look away, and don't blink.
DOCTOR: Good luck.